ANURAG KUMAR SRIVASTAVA

TECHNICAL LEAD

Key Skills

- Sprint Planning
- Backlog Refinement
- Problem Solving
- Test Engineer
- QA
- Functional Testing
- Software Testing
- Project Management
- Agile
- Scrum
- Waterfall
- Requirement Gathering
- Automation Testing
- Test Lead
- API Testing
- Web Services Testing
- Manual Testing

Certification

- Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certified
- Certified Scrum Master

Languages

- Hindi
- English

PHONE I (+91) 8318761751

EMAIL I anuraag.017@gmail.com

LOCATION I Gurugram, INDIA

EXPERIENCE I 9 Years 6 Months

Profile Summary

Worked as a QA Lead + Srum Master.

Experience in Project management, Requirement gathering, Problem solving, Backlog creation, Sprint planning, Waterfall and Agile methodology, Black box testing, API testing, RestAssured, MySQL and good understanding of automation testing (selenium, Java, Python, Protractor, JavaScript). Worked with tools like Jmeter, postman etc. Experience in QA domain as well as project handling, had managed different modules of projects and successfully delivered.

Work Experience

Technical Lead

Incedo

12/2020 - Present

Notice period is negotiable. Test Lead cum Scrum Master, having responsibility of creating test cases and execute them, creating test scripts for automation testing, sprint planning, backlog refinement. Working on agile methodology to deliver product qualitatively and efficiently. Performing Automation test through Protractor and JavaScript. Performing API tests via Postman, Database testing via PostgreSQL, SSMS, AWS cli. To deal with clients and manage quality of product from very beginning to the end of the project.

Senior Associate Technology

Digitigi Technologies 07/2018 - 03/2020

Test Engineer having responsibility of creating test

cases and execute them, creating test scripts for automation testing, working on agile methodology to deliver product qualitatively and efficiently. Managing website on Drupal 8. To deal with clients and manage quality of product from very beginning to the end of the project.

Test EngineerPromien Services pvt ltd.
07/2016 - 07/2018

Test Engineer having responsibility of creating test cases and execute them, creating test scripts for automation testing, working on agile methodology to deliver product qualitatively and efficiently.

Education

B.Tech/B.E. - Electronics/Telecommunication 2016

Gwalior Engineering College, Gwalior

Projects

New BMW Dealer Websites

23 Months

Creating and handling websites for BMW's Dealerships. And creating features like car comparison, EMI module, BSI/BRI module etc.

Z connect

15 Months

Corporate level legal issue handling website.

Provize

45 Months

Network planning tool